I was a blue-eyed, chubby-cheeked five-year-old
كنت طفلةً في الخامسة، ذات عينين زرقاوين وخدّين ممتلئين
when I joined my family on the picket line for the first time.
حين التحقت بعائلتي في صفوف الاعتصام لأول مرة.
My mom made me leave my dolls in the minivan.
جعلتني أمي أترك لعبي في الحافلة.
I'd stand on a street corner in the heavy Kansas humidity,
كنت أقف في زاوية الشارع في كنساس ذات الجو الرطب جداً،
surrounded by a few dozen relatives,
محاطةً بعشرات من أفراد عائلتي،
with my tiny fists clutching a sign that I couldn't read yet:
كنت أمسك بيدي الصغيرتين لافتة لم أكن أعرف أن أقرأها بعد:
"Gays are worthy of death."
" المثليّون يستحقون الموت."
This was the beginning.
كانت هذه هي البداية.
Our protests soon became a daily occurrence
أصبحت مظاهراتنا بعدها عادة يومية
and an international phenomenon,
وظاهرة عالمية،
and as a member of Westboro Baptist Church,
وكعضوة في الكنيسة المعمدانية لويستبورو،
I became a fixture on picket lines across the country.
أصبحت أيقونة أساسية في صفوف الاعتصامات عبر البلاد.
The end of my antigay picketing career
نهاية مسيرتي الاعتصامية ضد المثليّين،
and life as I knew it,
والحياة كما كنت أعرفها،
came 20 years later,
حدثت بعد 20 سنة،
triggered in part by strangers on Twitter
والتي حرّكها جزئياً أغراب التقيتهم على تويتر
who showed me the power of engaging the other.
والذين أروني قوة إدماج الآخر.
In my home,
في بيتي،
life was framed as an epic spiritual battle between good and evil.
كانت الحياة عبارة عن معركة ملحميّة بين الخير والشر.
The good was my church and its members,
الأخيار هم الكنيسة وأتباعها،
and the evil was everyone else.
والأشرار هم ما دونها.
My church's antics were such
قواعد كنيستي كانت بمثابة
that we were constantly at odds with the world,
خلاف دائم مع العالم،
and that reinforced our otherness on a daily basis.
وقد عزّز هذا اختلافنا في الحياة اليومية.
"Make a difference between the unclean and the clean,"
"فرّق بين ما هو نظيف وماهو دون ذلك،"
the verse says,
هكذا تقول الآية،
and so we did.
وهكذا فعلنا.
From baseball games to military funerals,
بداية من مباريات البيسبول إلى الجنائز العسكرية،
we trekked across the country with neon protest signs in hand
كنّا نجوب البلاد حاملين لافتات احتجاج بأيدينا
to tell others exactly how "unclean" they were
لنقول للآخرين كم هم "غير نظيفون"
and exactly why they were headed for damnation.
وكيف أنّ اللعنة ستحل عليهم لا محالة.
This was the focus of our whole lives.
كان هذا ما ترتكز عليه كلّ حياتنا.
This was the only way for me to do good in a world that sits in Satan's lap.
كانت هذه هي الطريقة الوحيدة بالنسبة لي لأقدم شيئاً للعالم المرتمي في حضن الشيطان.
And like the rest of my 10 siblings,
وكباقي إخوتي العشرة،
I believed what I was taught with all my heart,
كنت أؤمن تماماً بكل ما تعلمته،
and I pursued Westboro's agenda with a special sort of zeal.
و تتبعت أجندة الويستبورو بقدر خاص من الحماس.
In 2009, that zeal brought me to Twitter.
سنة 2009، كان ذلك الحماس هو ما دفعني لتويتر.
Initially, the people I encountered on the platform
في البداية، كان الناس الذين قابلتهم على المنصة
were just as hostile as I expected.
عنيفين كما توقعت.
They were the digital version of the screaming hordes
كانوا النسخة الرقمية للجحافل المدوّية
I'd been seeing at protests since I was a kid.
التي لطالما رأيتها في المظاهرات منذ كنت طفلة.
But in the midst of that digital brawl,
لكن وسط ذلك الشجار الرقمي،
a strange pattern developed.
تطوّر تموذجٌ غريب.
Someone would arrive at my profile with the usual rage and scorn,
كان أحدهم يدخل على صفحتي بنفس الغضب والإزدراء المعتادين،
I would respond with a custom mix of Bible verses, pop culture references
كنت أردّ بمزيج من آيات الإنجيل، ومراجع من الثقافة الشعبية
and smiley faces.
وأيقونات ضاحكة.
They would be understandably confused and caught off guard,
كانوا دون غرابة، ليصبحوا مشوشين فجأة.
but then a conversation would ensue.
لكن بعدها كان الحوار يبدأ.
And it was civil --
وقد كان حضارياً --
full of genuine curiosity on both sides.
مليئاً بالفضول الصادق من كلا الجانبين.
How had the other come to such outrageous conclusions about the world?
كيف توصّل الآخر لهذه الخلاصات الحانقة عن العالم؟
Sometimes the conversation even bled into real life.
في بعض الأحيان كان الحوار ينتقل إلى العالم الحقيقي.
People I'd sparred with on Twitter
كان بعض ممن غردت معهم على تويتر
would come out to the picket line to see me
يأتون إلى صف الاعتصام لرؤيتي
when I protested in their city.
حينما كنت أتظاهر في مدينتهم.
A man named David was one such person.
رجل يدعى (ديفيد) كان أحد هؤلاء.
He ran a blog called "Jewlicious,"
كان يدير مدونةً تسمى "جويليشيوس،"
and after several months of heated but friendly arguments online,
وبعد شهور من النقاش الحامي لكن الودي على الإنترنت،
he came out to see me at a picket in New Orleans.
جاء ليراني في اعتصام في نيو أورلينز.
He brought me a Middle Eastern dessert from Jerusalem, where he lives,
أحضر لي حلويات شرق أوسطية من القدس حيث يعيش،
and I brought him kosher chocolate
وأحضرت له شكولاتة كوشير
and held a "God hates Jews" sign.
مع لافتةٍ في يدي مكتوب عليها "الرب يكره اليهود."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
There was no confusion about our positions,
كانت مواقفنا واضحةً جداً،
but the line between friend and foe was becoming blurred.
لكن الحدود بين الصديق والعدو أصبحت مبهمة.
We'd started to see each other as human beings,
أصبحنا نرى بعضنا كإنسانين،
and it changed the way we spoke to one another.
وقد غيّر هذا طريقة حديثنا لبعضنا البعض.
It took time,
أخذ الأمر بعض الوقت،
but eventually these conversations planted seeds of doubt in me.
لكن في النهاية زرعت هذه الحوارات بذور الشك فيّ.
My friends on Twitter took the time to understand Westboro's doctrines,
أخذ زملائي بعض الوقت لفهم عقائد الويستبورو،
and in doing so,
وبذلك،
they were able to find inconsistencies I'd missed my entire life.
فقد استطاعوا إيجاد بعض الاختلالات التي لم أنتبه لها طوال حياتي.
Why did we advocate the death penalty for gays
لم ندافع عن عقوبة الإعدام للمثليين
when Jesus said, "Let he who is without sin cast the first stone?"
حين يقول المسيح"دع من هو بلا خطيئةٍ أن يُلقي بالحجر الأول؟"
How could we claim to love our neighbor
كيف لنا أن ندّعي حبّ الجار
while at the same time praying for God to destroy them?
بينما ندعو الرب في نفس الوقت أن يدمرهم؟
The truth is that the care shown to me by these strangers on the internet
الحقيقة أن الاهتمام الذي أظهره لي هؤلاء الغرباء على الانترنت
was itself a contradiction.
كان تناقضاً في حد ذاته.
It was growing evidence
كان تأكيداً متزايداً
that people on the other side were not the demons I'd been led to believe.
أن الناس الموجودين على الطرف الآخر ليسوا شياطيناً كما صوّر لي.
These realizations were life-altering.
غيّرت تلك الاكتشاقات حياتي.
Once I saw that we were not the ultimate arbiters of divine truth
حالما رأيت أنّنا لسنا الحكّام المطلقين الذين يحملون الحقيقة الإلهية
but flawed human beings,
بل بشراً يخطئون،
I couldn't pretend otherwise.
لم يعد بإمكاني إدعاء عكس ذلك.
I couldn't justify our actions --
لم أعد أستطع تبرير أفعالنا --
especially our cruel practice of protesting funerals
خصوصاً خروجنا الفظيع للتظاهر في الجنائز
and celebrating human tragedy.
والاحتفال بالآلام الإنسانية.
These shifts in my perspective
هذه التحوّلات في رؤيتي
contributed to a larger erosion of trust in my church,
ساهمت مساهمةً كبيرة في تراجع ثقتي اتجاه كنيستي،
and eventually it made it impossible for me to stay.
وفي النهاية جعلت من المستحيل أن أبقى هناك.
In spite of overwhelming grief and terror, I left Westboro in 2012.
على الرغم من الحزن الكبير والرعب، تركت ويستبورو سنة 2012.
In those days just after I left,
في تلك الأيام بعد أن غادرت بقليل،
the instinct to hide was almost paralyzing.
كانت غريزة التخفي مخيفةً للغاية.
I wanted to hide from the judgement of my family,
كنت أريد أن أتوارى عن حكم عائلتي،
who I knew would never speak to me again --
التي كنت أعرف أنهم لن يكلموني بعدها أبداً --
people whose thoughts and opinions had meant everything to me.
هؤلاء الناس الذين كانت أفكارهم وآراؤهم تعني لي الشيء الكثير.
And I wanted to hide from the world I'd rejected for so long --
وأردت أن أتوارى عن العالم الذي رفضته لوقت طويل --
people who had no reason at all to give me a second chance
هؤلاء الناس الذين لم يكونوا مجبرين على منحي فرصةً ثانية
after a lifetime of antagonism.
بعد حياةٍ طويلة من الكراهية.
And yet, unbelievably,
لكن، وعلى نحو لا يصدق،
they did.
منحوني إياها.
The world had access to my past because it was all over the internet --
كان العالم يعرف ماضيّ لأنه موجود على الإنترنت --
thousands of tweets and hundreds of interviews,
آلاف التغريدات ومئات الحوارات،
everything from local TV news to "The Howard Stern Show" --
كل شيء من أخبار القنوات المحلية حتي برنامج "ذ هاورد ستيرن شو" --
but so many embraced me with open arms anyway.
لكن العديد منهم استقبلوني بصدر رحب رغم كل ذلك.
I wrote an apology for the harm I'd caused,
كتبت رسالة اعتذار للألم الذي سببته،
but I also knew that an apology could never undo any of it.
لكنني كنت أعلم أن الاعتذار لن يمحو أيّاً منه أبداً.
All I could do was try to build a new life
كل ما استطعت فعله هو محاولة بناء حياةٍ جديدة
and find a way somehow to repair some of the damage.
و إيجاد طريقةٍ ما لتصحيح بعض من الضرر.
People had every reason to doubt my sincerity,
كان من حق الناس التشكيك في صدقي،
but most of them didn't.
لكن أغلبيتهم لم تفعل.
And --
و --
given my history,
بالنظر لتاريخي،
it was more than I could've hoped for --
كان ذلك أكثر مما كنت أتمناه --
forgiveness and the benefit of the doubt.
التسامح وافتراض حسن النيّة.
It still amazes me.
ما يزال هذا يدهشني.
I spent my first year away from home
قضيت سنتي الأولى بعيداً عن الديار
adrift with my younger sister,
أسير بلا هدف بصحبة أختي الصغرى،
who had chosen to leave with me.
التي اختارت أن تغادر معي.
We walked into an abyss,
كنّا نسير نحو الهاوية،
but we were shocked to find the light and a way forward
لكنّنا صدمنا حينما رأينا النور وطريقاً نحو الأمام
in the same communities we'd targeted for so long.
داخل نفس المجتمعات التي استهدفناها لوقت طويل.
David,
(ديفيد)،
my "Jewlicious" friend from Twitter,
صديقي من تويتر صاحب مدونة "جويليشيوس"،
invited us to spend time among a Jewish community in Los Angeles.
دعانا لقضاء بعض الوقت مع الطائفة اليهودية في لوس أنجلوس.
We slept on couches in the home of a Hasidic rabbi and his wife
نمنا على أرائك منزل الحاخام (هازيديك) وزوجته
and their four kids --
وأولادهم الأربعة --
the same rabbi that I'd protested three years earlier
الحاخام نفسه الذي تظاهرت ضدّه قبل ثلاث سنوات مضت
with a sign that said, "Your rabbi is a whore."
وأنا أحمل لافتة تقول، "حاخامكم عاهرة."
We spent long hours talking about theology and Judaism and life
قضينا ساعات طوال نتكلم عن اللاهوت واليهودية والحياة
while we washed dishes in their kosher kitchen
ونحن ننظف الأواني في مطبخهم ذي الطقوس اليهودية
and chopped vegetables for dinner.
ونقطع الخضار لتحضير العشاء.
They treated us like family.
عاملونا كأفراد من عائلتهم.
They held nothing against us,
لم يكونوا يحملون أي ضغينة اتجاهنا،
and again I was astonished.
مرة أخرى كنت مندهشة.
That period was full of turmoil,
كانت تلك المرحلة مضطربةً جداً،
but one part I've returned to often
لكن كانت هناك جزئية أعود إليها غالباً
is a surprising realization I had during that time --
وهي الإدراك المفاجئ الذي حصل لي في تلك الفترة --
that it was a relief and a privilege to let go of the harsh judgments
وهي أنه كان من المريح والمشرّف التخلص من الأحكام المؤذية
that instinctively ran through my mind about nearly every person I saw.
التي كانت تدور تلقائياً في رأسي حيال أي شخص أراه تقريباً.
I realized that now I needed to learn.
أدركت الآن أنه كان علي أن أتعلم.
I needed to listen.
كان علي أن أنصت.
This has been at the front of my mind lately,
وهذا ما أصبح عليه عقلي مؤخراً،
because I can't help but see in our public discourse
لأنني لم أعد أتحمل رؤية ما يجري عل الساحة العامة
so many of the same destructive impulses that ruled my former church.
من الانفعالات المدمرة ذاتها التي كانت تحكم كنيستي السابقة.
We celebrate tolerance and diversity more than at any other time in memory,
نحن نحتفي بالتسامح والتعاون أكثر من أي شيء في تاريخنا،
and still we grow more and more divided.
لكنّنا مازلنا نتفرق أكثر فأكثر.
We want good things --
نريد الحصول على الأشياء الجيّدة --
justice, equality, freedom, dignity, prosperity --
العدالة، المساواة، الحرية، الكرامة، الازدهار --
but the path we've chosen
لكن الطريق الذي اخترناه
looks so much like the one I walked away from four years ago.
يبدو جداً كذلك الذي تركته منذ أربع سنوات.
We've broken the world into us and them,
قسّمنا العالم إلى " نحن" و"هم،"
only emerging from our bunkers long enough
لنخرج من مخابئنا التي سكناها طويلاً
to lob rhetorical grenades at the other camp.
لنلقي قنابل بلاغية على المعسكر الآخر.
We write off half the country as out-of-touch liberal elites
نقصي نصف البلد على أنهم نخبةٌ ليبرالية بعيدة
or racist misogynist bullies.
أو متنمرون عنصريّون يكرهون النساء.
No nuance, no complexity, no humanity.
لاتحايل، لا تعقيد، لاإنسانية.
Even when someone does call for empathy and understanding for the other side,
حتى و إن دعا أحدهم إلى التعاطف وفهم الطرف الآخر
the conversation nearly always devolves
تتحول المحادثة في كل مرة
into a debate about who deserves more empathy.
إلى نقاش حول من يستحق تعاطفاً أكثر.
And just as I learned to do,
وكما تعلمت،
we routinely refuse to acknowledge the flaws in our positions
نرفض أن نعترف بالعيوب التي تعتري مواقفنا
or the merits in our opponent's.
أو النقاط التي تحسب لمعارضينا.
Compromise is anathema.
التوافق أمر بغيض.
We even target people on our own side when they dare to question the party line.
حتى أننا نهاجم الناس الذين هم على جانبنا حين يتجرؤون على مساءلة خط نظامنا.
This path has brought us cruel, sniping, deepening polarization,
جعلنا هذا الطريق متوحّشين، قنّاصين، وزاد من حدة القطبية،
and even outbreaks of violence.
حتى أنه تفرّع ليصبح عنفاً.
I remember this path.
أتذكر ذلك الطريق.
It will not take us where we want to go.
لن يأخذنا إلى حيث نريد أن نذهب.
What gives me hope is that we can do something about this.
ما يعطيني أملاً الآن هو أنه يمكننا فعل شيء حيال هذا الأمر.
The good news is that it's simple,
والخبر السار هو أن هذا سهل،
and the bad news is that it's hard.
والخبر السيء هو أن هذا صعب.
We have to talk and listen to people we disagree with.
علينا أن نتحدث وننصت إلى الناس الذين نختلف معهم.
It's hard because we often can't fathom
الأمر صعب لأنه غالباً لا يمكننا الفهم بعمق
how the other side came to their positions.
كيف وصل الطرف الآخر إلى هذه المواقف.
It's hard because righteous indignation,
صعب بسبب استياء الصالحين،
that sense of certainty that ours is the right side,
حس اليقين أن طرفنا هو الطرف الصائب،
is so seductive.
مثيرٌ للغاية.
It's hard because it means extending empathy and compassion
هذا صعب لأنه يعني أن نوصل التعاطف والتسامح
to people who show us hostility and contempt.
للناس الذين أظهروا لنا العنف والازدراء
The impulse to respond in kind is so tempting,
ورغبة الردّ بالمثل مغرية جداً،
but that isn't who we want to be.
لكن ليس هذا ما نريد أن نكونه.
We can resist.
يمكن أن نقاوم.
And I will always be inspired to do so by those people I encountered on Twitter,
وسيظل دائما الناس الذين التقيتهم على تويتر مصدر إلهامي،
apparent enemies who became my beloved friends.
أعدائي من الخارج الذين أصبحوا أصدقائي الأعزاء.
And in the case of one particularly understanding and generous guy,
وفي حالةٍ خاصة، هناك شخص كان متفهماً و كريما للغاية،
my husband.
زوجي.
There was nothing special about the way I responded to him.
لم يكن هناك ما يجعل طريقة إجابتي له مميزة.
What was special was their approach.
ماكان مميزاً هي طريقتهم.
I thought about it a lot over the past few years
فكرت بها كثيراً خلال السنوات القليلة الماضية
and I found four things they did differently
فوجدت أن هناك أربع أشياء قاموا بها على نحو مختلف
that made real conversation possible.
مما جعل المحادثة الحقيقية أمراً ممكناً.
These four steps were small but powerful,
تلك الخطوات الأربع كانت بسيطة لكن قوية،
and I do everything I can to employ them in difficult conversations today.
واليوم أقوم بكل ما في وسعي لأستخدمها في المحادثات الصعبة.
The first is don't assume bad intent.
الأولى: لا تفترض النيّة السيئة.
My friends on Twitter realized
أدرك أصدقائي على تويتر
that even when my words were aggressive and offensive,
أنه حتى لو كانت كلماتي جارحة وقاسية،
I sincerely believed I was doing the right thing.
فقد كنت مؤمنة أنني أقوم بالشيء الصحيح.
Assuming ill motives almost instantly cuts us off
افتراض دوافع سيئة، يمنعنا تماماً وبسرعة
from truly understanding why someone does and believes as they do.
من الفهم الحقيقي للسبب الذي يجعل شخصاً ما يقوم بما يقوم به.
We forget that they're a human being
ننسى أنه إنسان
with a lifetime of experience that shaped their mind,
لديه تجربة حياتية شكّلت أفكاره،
and we get stuck on that first wave of anger,
ونبقى عالقين في موجة الغضب الأولى تلك،
and the conversation has a very hard time ever moving beyond it.
فيكون من الصعب جداً على المحادثة أن تتجاوزها.
But when we assume good or neutral intent,
لكن حين نفترض نيّة حسنة أو محايدة،
we give our minds a much stronger framework for dialogue.
نعطي لدماغنا إطاراً أقوى للحوار.
The second is ask questions.
الثاني: أن نطرح الأسئلة.
When we engage people across ideological divides,
حين نقوم بدمج الناس من جميع الأطياف الأيديولوجية،
asking questions helps us map the disconnect
فإن طرح الأسئلة يساعدنا على تحديد مكان عدم التوافق
between our differing points of view.
بين وجهات نظرنا المتفاوتة.
That's important because we can't present effective arguments
هذا مهمٌ لأنه لا يمكننا تقديم حججٍ قوية
if we don't understand where the other side is actually coming from
إن لم نفهم دوافع ومصادر الطرف الآخر
and because it gives them an opportunity to point out flaws in our positions.
ولأنها ستمنحهم فرصة تحديد العيوب في مواقفنا.
But asking questions serves another purpose;
لكن طرح الأسئلة يخدم هدفا آخر،
it signals to someone that they're being heard.
فهي إشارة للشخص الآخر أنه مسموع.
When my friends on Twitter stopped accusing
حينما توقف أصدقائي على تويتر عن الهجوم
and started asking questions,
وبدؤوا في طرح الأسئلة،
I almost automatically mirrored them.
أصبحت تلقائياً أقوم بما يقومون به.
Their questions gave me room to speak,
منحتني أسئلتهم مجالاً لأتحدث،
but they also gave me permission to ask them questions
لكنهم أيضاً سمحوا لي بأن أسألهم
and to truly hear their responses.
وأن أنصت فعلاً لأجوبتهم.
It fundamentally changed the dynamic of our conversation.
وهذا غيّر جذرياً طريقة المحادثة.
The third is stay calm.
الثالث: أن تبقى هادئاً.
This takes practice and patience,
وهذا يتطلب تمرناً و صبراً،
but it's powerful.
لكنه مؤثر.
At Westboro, I learned not to care how my manner of speaking affected others.
في ويستبرو تعلمت ألا أحفل كيف يمكن لطريقة حديثي أن تؤثّر على الآخرين.
I thought my rightness justified my rudeness --
كنت أعتقد أن صوابي يبرر وقاحتي --
harsh tones, raised voices, insults, interruptions --
نبرة صوتٍ حادة، صوتٌ مرتفع، شتم، مقاطعة --
but that strategy is ultimately counterproductive.
لكن تلك الاستراتيجية غير مجدية دون شك.
Dialing up the volume and the snark is natural in stressful situations,
رفع الصوت والصراخ طبيعي في حالات التوتر،
but it tends to bring the conversation to an unsatisfactory, explosive end.
لكنه غالباً ما يجرّ المحادثة لنهاية نارية وغير مرضية.
When my husband was still just an anonymous Twitter acquaintance,
حينما كان زوجي لا يزال شخصاً مجهول الهوية على تويتر،
our discussions frequently became hard and pointed,
كانت دائماً ما تصبح نقاشاتنا حادةً وصعبة،
but we always refused to escalate.
لكنّنا كنّا دائما نرفض التصعيد.
Instead, he would change the subject.
عوضاً عن ذلك، كان يفضّل تغيير الموضوع.
He would tell a joke or recommend a book
كان يقول مزحةً أو يقترح كتاباً
or gently excuse himself from the conversation.
أو يعتذر بكل لباقة عن إتمام الحوار.
We knew the discussion wasn't over,
كنّا نعرف أن النقاش لم ينته،
just paused for a time to bring us back to an even keel.
لكنه توقف فقط حتى نعود إلى مستوى متساوٍ.
People often lament that digital communication makes us less civil,
غالباً ما يشتكي الناس أن التواصل الرقمي يجعلنا أقل تحضراً،
but this is one advantage that online conversations have over in-person ones.
لكن هذه صفة إيجابية للمحادثات الرقمية بالمقارنة مع المحادثة وجهاً لوجه.
We have a buffer of time and space
لدينا متسع من الوقت والفضاء
between us and the people whose ideas we find so frustrating.
بيننا وبين الناس الذين تجعلنا أفكارهم نحسّ بالحنق.
We can use that buffer.
يمكننا استعمال ذلك المتسع.
Instead of lashing out, we can pause, breathe,
عوضاً عن فقدان السيطرة، يمكننا أن نتوقف ونأخذ نفساً عميقاً،
change the subject or walk away,
نغيّر الموضوع أو نغادر،
and then come back to it when we're ready.
ونعود بعدها حين نكون جاهزين.
And finally ...
و أخيراً ...
make the argument.
قدّم الحجة.
This might seem obvious,
قد يبدو هذا بديهياً،
but one side effect of having strong beliefs
لكن المشكل في حمل معتقداتٍ قوية
is that we sometimes assume
هي أننا غالباً ما نفترض
that the value of our position is or should be obvious and self-evident,
أن قيمة ما نقدمه هي، أو يجب أن تكون بديهية،
that we shouldn't have to defend our positions
هوأنّه ليس علينا أن ندافع عن مواقفنا
because they're so clearly right and good
لأنها صائبة وجيدة على نحو جليٍ
that if someone doesn't get it, it's their problem --
حيث أنّه إن لم يفهمها شخص ما، فتلك مشكلته --
that it's not my job to educate them.
ليس عليّ أن أعلمهم.
But if it were that simple,
لكن لو كان الأمر بتلك البساطة،
we would all see things the same way.
لكنا رأينا الأشياء كلها بنفس الطريقة.
As kind as my friends on Twitter were,
كما فعل أصدقائي بكل لطف على تويتر،
if they hadn't actually made their arguments,
لو لم يقدّموا حججهم،
it would've been so much harder for me to see the world in a different way.
لكان من الصعب عليّ أن أرى العالم بطريقة مختلفة.
We are all a product of our upbringing,
كلّنا نتاج تربيتنا،
and our beliefs reflect our experiences.
ومعتقداتنا تعكس تجاربنا.
We can't expect others to spontaneously change their own minds.
لا يمكننا أن نتوقع من الآخرين أن يغيّروا مواقفهم بشكل تلقائي.
If we want change,
إن أردنا التغيير،
we have to make the case for it.
علينا أن نصنع حالة له.
My friends on Twitter didn't abandon their beliefs or their principles --
لم يتخلّ أصدقائي على تويتر عن معتقداتهم أو مبادئهم --
only their scorn.
تخلّوا فقط عن الازدراء.
They channeled their infinitely justifiable offense
لقد حوّلوا اتجاه الإساءة التي لها مبرراتها الكثيرة
and came to me with pointed questions tempered with kindness and humor.
وجاؤوا إليّ بأسئلة يلفها العطف والمرح.
They approached me as a human being,
لقد تقرّبوا منّي على أنّني إنسانة،
and that was more transformative
وهذا ما شكّل ذلك التحول على نحو أكبر
than two full decades of outrage, disdain and violence.
من عقدين كاملين من الغضب، والتحقير والعنف.
I know that some might not have the time or the energy or the patience
أعرف أنّ هناك من لم يكن لديه الوقت أو الطاقة أو الصبر
for extensive engagement,
للانخراط على نحو أكبر،
but as difficult as it can be,
لكن رغم ما يبدو عليه الأمر من صعوبة،
reaching out to someone we disagree with
فإن التقرّب من شخص نختلف معه
is an option that is available to all of us.
هو خيارٌ متاحٌ لنا جميعاً.
And I sincerely believe that we can do hard things,
وأعتقد بكل صدق أنه يمكننا القيام بأشياء صعبة،
not just for them but for us and our future.
ليس فقط من أجلهم، لكن من أجلنا ومن أجل مستقبلنا.
Escalating disgust and intractable conflict
تصعيد الاشمئزاز والصراع
are not what we want for ourselves,
ليس هذا ما نريده لأنفسنا،
or our country
لبلدنا،
or our next generation.
للجيل القادم.
My mom said something to me a few weeks before I left Westboro,
قالت لي أمي شيئاً قبل أسابيع من مغادرتي لويستبرو،
when I was desperately hoping
حين كنت آمل بشكل يائس
there was a way I could stay with my family.
أن تكون هناك طريقة ما كي أظلّ مع عائلتي.
People I have loved with every pulse of my heart
الناس الذين أحببتهم من كلّ قلبي
since even before I was that chubby-cheeked five-year-old,
حتى قبل أن أكون تلك الطفلة ذات الخدّين الممتلئتين في الخامسة من عمرها،
standing on a picket line holding a sign I couldn't read.
التي تقف في صفوف الاعتصام تحمل لافتة لا تستطيع قراءتها.
She said, "You're just a human being,
قالت،"أنت إنسانة فحسب،
my dear, sweet child."
ياطفلتي الحلوة الحبيبة."
She was asking me to be humble --
كانت تطلب مني أن أكون متواضعة --
not to question but to trust God and my elders.
ألا أسأل، أن أثق في الرب وفي من يكبرونني سناً.
But to me, she was missing the bigger picture --
لكن بالنسبة لي، فقد فوتت فرصة رؤية الصورة الكبرى --
that we're all just human beings.
هي أنّنا جميعنا بشر.
That we should be guided by that most basic fact,
وأنّه علينا أن نلتمس الطريق من خلال هذا المعطى البسيط،
and approach one another with generosity and compassion.
وأن نقترب من بعضنا البعض بكرمٍ وعطف.
Each one of us contributes to the communities
كل منّا يساهم في المجموعات
and the cultures and the societies that we make up.
والثقافات والمجتمعات التي نبنيها.
The end of this spiral of rage and blame begins with one person
نهاية دوامة الغضب واللوم هذه تبدأ بشخصٍ واحدٍ
who refuses to indulge these destructive, seductive impulses.
يرفض أن يغوص في هذه الانفعالات المثيرة والمدمرة.
We just have to decide that it's going to start with us.
علينا فقط أن نقرر أنها ستبدأ بنا.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)